Guide to the Sharon and Lew Andre Mathews collection, 1974-2018 MS 829
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Sharon and Lew Andre Mathews collection
1975-2018
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Mathews, Lew Andre
MS 829
2.82 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0829aip_001 (2.82 GB)
7.11 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0829aip_002 (7.11 GB)
18.7 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0829aip_003 (18.7 GB)
This collection contains digital media that charts the music career of Lew Andrew Mathews, as well as the life and career of Sharon Mathews.
Biographical / Historical
Hailing from New York, Sharon Slane moved to Houston in the mid-1970s. She worked at a variety of music venues, including Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant, Houlihan's No. 2, Rockefeller's, among others.
After growing up in a military household, Lew Andre Mathews moved to Houston in 1972. He played at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant, but then traveled throughout Texas with a variety of bands. He played lead guitar with Danny Epps band, as well as joined the Hemmer Ridge Mountain Boys.
Sharon Slane and Lew Andre Mathews married in the mid-1980s. Soon after, they relocated to Austin. In 1989, Lew Andre Mathews took a job at UCLA. They began performing in and around California until they moved back to Texas. Lew Andre Mathews continues to perform and is in the band The Patrons.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains scanned images of photographs, fliers, posters, as well as digitized and born digital video.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Request access to this digital material (stored on Fondren Library's nearline / non-public server) by contacting Woodson Research Center staff at woodson@rice.edu. Please use the Identifier number in your request.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Sharon Mathews and Lew Andre Mathews in 2018.
Index Terms
Subjects
Folk music -- Texas -- Houston
Document Types
Folk music; Folk-rock music
Subjects (Persons)
Mathews, Sharon
- Series I: Digital images
  - Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant, 1975-1995
    Scope and Contents
    Items are master tifs and access jpgs.
  - Business cards, 1975-2005
  - Calendars, 1978-1979
  - Fliers, 1990s-2000s
  - Freddy Fender, 1970s
  - Hemmer Ridge Mountain Boys, 1970s
  - Houlahan's No. 2, 1970s
  - Lucinda Williams, 1970s-1990s
  - Mickey White, 1980s
  - News clippings, 1979-2016
  - Rex Bell, 1978
  - Richard Dobson, 1970s-2010s
  - Set lists, n.d.
  - Shake Russell, 1978
  - Sharon and Lew Andre Mathews, 1970s
  - Lew Andre Mathews, 1970s-1990s
  - Sharon Mathews, 1970s-2000s
  - Stephen Jarrard, 1990s
  - Townes Van Zandt, 1970s
  - Unidentified, 1970s
  - Vince Bell, 1988
- Series II: Video
  - Richard Dobson house concert, 1994-03-23
    This digitized video file consists of one master copy mpg and one access copy mp4. Contents include: Richard Dobson house concert at the Mathews home.
  - Sharon Mathews oral history, 2018-06-28
    This born digital video file consists of one master copy mp4.
  - Lew Andre Mathews oral history, 2018-06-28